Generative adversarial networks are a kind of generative model.
生成对抗网络是一种生成模型
Earlier in this Nanodegree,
在该纳米学位的较早部分
you've seen how recurrent networks can be trained as generative models of text.
你已经了解到如何把循环网络作为文本的生成模型进行训练
Recurrent text models generate assignats one word at a time.
循环文本模型一次生成一个词语
It's also possible to make one word at a time,
也可以依次产生一个词语
style models per images,
每个图像的风格模型
where the model generates the image one pixel at a time.
其中模型每次生成图像的一个像素
In general, this strategy is called,
一般说来 这种策略叫做
'fully visible belief networks' going back to the '90s or auto regressive models,
全可见信念网络 可以追溯到 1990 年代 或是自动回归模型
as these models were renamed when they were rediscovered later.
因为再次发现这些模型后 进行重新命名
But, what if we would like to generate
不过 如果我们想生成
an entire output value such as an entire image in one shot?
整个输出值 如一次生成整个图像 应该怎么办呢？
GANs are a kind of generative model that let's us generate a whole image in parallel.
生成对抗网络可以让我们一次性生成整个图像
Along with several other kinds of generative models,
与其他几种生成模型一样
GANs use a differentiable function
生成对抗网络使用可微函数
represented by a neural network as a generator network.
在神经网络中表现为生成器网络
The generator network takes random noise as input,
生成器网络利用随机噪音作为输入
then runs that noise through a differentiable function to
然后通过可微函数运行噪音
transform the noise and reshape it to have recognizable structure.
然后转变噪音 重新塑造为可以识别的结构
The output of the generator network is a realistic image.
生成器网络的输出是真实图像
The choice of the random input noise
随机选择输入噪音
determines which image will come out of the generator network.
决定了生成器网络输出的图像类型
Running the generator network with
利用许多不同的输入噪音值
many different input noise values produces many different realistic output images.
运行生成器网络 会生成各种不同的真实图像
The goal is for these images to be fair samples from the distribution over real data.
这些图像的目的在于成为从分布中真实数据的良好样本
Of course, the generator net doesn't start out producing realistic images.
当然生成器网络不会立即生成真实图像
It has to be trained.
需要进行训练
The training process for a generative model is very
生成模型的训练过程
different from the training process for a supervised learning model.
与监督学习模型的训练过程不同
For a supervised learning model,
在监督学习模型中
we show the model an image of a traffic light and we tell it,
我们向模型展现交通信号灯的一个图像 我们告诉它
this is a traffic light.
这是交通信号灯
For a generative model,
在生成模型中
there's no output to associate with each image.
没有输出和每个图像是关联的
We just show the model a lot of images and ask it to
我们向模型展现许多图像
make more images that come from the same probability distribution.
让它从相同概率分布中得到更多图片
But how do we actually get the model to do that?
但是我们怎么让模型做到这一点呢？
Most generative models are trained by adjusting the parameters to
通过调整参数 最大化概率 训练生成模型
maximize the probability that the generator net will generate the training data set.
这样生成器网络会生成训练数据集
Unfortunately for a lot of interesting models,
不幸的是 对于许多有趣的模型
it can be very difficult to compute this probability.
它很难计算这个概率
Most generative models get around that with some kind of approximation.
大多数生成网络采用近似法解决这个问题
GANs use an approximation where a second network,
生成对抗网络使用近似法 其中
called the discriminator, learns to guide the generator.
第二个网络叫做判别器 学习指导生成器
The discriminator is just a regular neural net classifier,
判别器是常规的神经网络分类器
like you have all seen several times by now.
正如你之前几次见到的那样
During the training process,
在训练过程中
the discriminator is shown real images from the training data half
一半时间 判别器收到来自训练数据中的真实图像
the time and fake images from the generator the other half of the time.
另一半时间收到来自生成器中的虚假图像
The discriminator is trained to output the probability that the input is real.
训练判别器输出那些真实输入的概率
So it tries to assign a probability near 1 to real images,
对于真实图像 它试图对概率赋值接近 1
and a probability near zero to fake images.
而对于虚假图像 对概率的赋值接近 0
Meanwhile the generator tries to do the opposite.
与此同时 生成器所做的恰好相反
It is trained to try to output images that the discriminator
通过训练 它输出判别器
will assign probability near one of being real.
赋值概率接近 1 的图像
Over time, the generator is forced to produce
经过一段时间后 生成器被迫产生
more realistic outputs in order to fool the discriminator.
更加真实的输出 从而欺骗判别器
The generator takes random noise values Z and maps them to put values X.
生成器利用随机噪音值 Z 映射它们得到值 X
Wherever the generator maps more values of Z,
在生成器映射更多值 Z 的地方
the probability distribution over X,
模型中展现出 X 的概率分布
represented by the model, becomes denser.
变得更加密集
The discriminator outputs high values wherever
在真实数据的密度大于生成数据密度的地方
the density of real data is greater than the density of generated data.
判别器会输出较高值
The generator changes the samples it produces to
生成器改变了它生成的样本
move uphill along the function learned by the discriminator.
通过判别器的学习 沿着函数上升
In other words, the generator moves its samples into
换句话说 生成器把样本移动到
areas where the model distribution is not yet dense enough.
其他模型分布不够密集的区域
Eventually the generator's distribution matches the real distribution,
最后生成器的分布与真实分布相匹配
and the discriminator has to output a probability of one half everywhere because
判别器输出各处概率的一半
every point is equally likely to be generated by
因为每个点可能一半是通过真实数据生成的
the real data set as to be generated by the model.
一半是通过模型生成的
The two densities are equal.
两个密度是相等的
We can think of this process as being like
我们可以认为这个过程类似于
a competition between counterfeiters and police.
造假者和警察的竞争
The generator net is like a group of
生成器网络像是一群
counterfeiters trying to produce fake money and pass it off as real.
造假者企图制造假币 以假乱真
The police try to catch counterfeiters using
警察努力抓捕使用假币的造假者
fake money but still want to let everyone else spend their real money.
但还是希望其他人使用真币
Over time the police get better at detecting
经过一段时间 警察越来越擅长检测假币
counterfeit money and the counterfeiters get better at faking it.
而造假者越来越擅长造假币
Eventually the counterfeiters are forced to make perfect replicas of real money.
最后造假者被迫制造真币的完美复制版
When we train a simple GAN on the CIFAR-10 data set,
当我们在 CIFAR-10 数据集上训练简单的生成对抗网络时
we can watch it begin by generating random images,
我们观察到它起初生成随机图像
then gradually learn to generate horses,
然后逐渐学会生成马
airplanes, trucks and so on.
飞机 卡车等图像
That's the basic idea of how GANs work.
这就是生成对抗网络的运行原理
In the next few lessons,
在接下来几节课中
we'll explain more of the theory of
我们会介绍更多生成对抗网络的理论
GANs and some of the tips and tricks for making them work well.
和更好使用生成对抗网络的技巧